钱德勒  钱德勒
Chandler!!! Chandler!!!
钱德勒  我从窗户看见了
Chandler, I saw what you were doing through the window!
我看见你在对我妹做什么了  你给我出来
I saw what you were doing to my sister! Now get out here!
听着  我们玩得很开心
Wow! Listen, we had a good run.
总共四个月  五个月吗
What was it? Four? Five months?
很多人一辈子也没谈过这么久的恋爱
I mean, that's more than most people have in a lifetime!
再见  保重  再见了
So, good-bye, take care, bye-bye then!
你干什么
What are you doing?!
我要跑路
Oh, I'm going on the lamb.
钱德勒  过来  我应付得了罗斯
Come on Chandler, come on, I can handle Ross.
等一下
Hold on!
罗斯老哥  有什么事
Hey Ross. What's up bro?
你干了什么好事
What the hell are you doing?!!
发生什么事了
Hey, what's-what's going on?!
我想  罗斯发现我和莫妮卡的事了
Well, I think, I think Ross knows about me and Monica.
哥们  他人就在那里
Dude! He's right there!
我以为你是我最好的朋友  这可是我妹妹
I thought you were my best friend, this is my sister!
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹  我真不敢相信
My best friend and my sister! I-I cannot believe this!
我们不是玩玩而已
Look, we're not just messing around!
我爱她  我爱着她
I love her. Okay, I'm in love with her.
抱歉让你这样发现
I'm so sorry that you had to find out this way.
对不起  但是真的  我也爱他
I'm sorry, but it's true, I love him too.
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹
My best friend and my sister!
我真不敢相信
I cannot believe this.
你们也想抱抱吧  大消息哦
You guys probably wanna get some hugs in too, huh? Big news!
不用了  我们知道一阵子了
Awww, no, it's okay, we've actually known for a while.
什么  你们知道
What? What? What?! You guys knew?
你们都知道  却没告诉我
You all knew and you didn't tell me?!!
罗斯  我们很担心你
Well, Ross, we were worried about you.
不知道你会有什么反应
We didn't know how you were going to react.
你们担心我
You were worried about me?
不知道我会有什么反应
You didn't know how I was going to react?
好吧
Okay, all right, whew!
我们要不要清个场
What do you say we all clear out of here
让这对小情人继续办事
and let these two lovebirds get back down to business?
我只是说说
Hey-hey-hey, I-I-I'm just talking here,
上你妹的是他
he-he's the one doing your sister.
你们猜我想到什么
Hey, you know what I just realized?
要是你们生了小孩
If you guys ever have kids...
我们生小孩
Whoa-whoa-whoa! We're having kids?!
教父是我的
I call Godfather!
哪能这样用说的
You can't just call Godfather.
你不觉得教父应该是舅舅来做吗
Don't you think her brother should be Godfather?
当然  你有心就应该先喊
Sure, if you cared enough to call it first.
你们想得太远了
Guys, you're a few steps ahead of us.
十万八千里的远
Yeah, big zero gravity moon steps.
我刚想到一样最棒的结婚礼物
Oh! Oh, I just thought of the greatest wedding gift to get you.
我跟你送  我什么都想不到
Ooh, I'll go in on that with you! I couldn't think of anything.
凯蒂  各位  这是凯蒂
Oh, hey Katie! Everyone, this is Katie.
可以走了吗
So, are you ready to go?
可以  我先上个厕所
Yeah, I just gotta run to the bathroom.
往后走
Oh sure, right back there.
我们午餐要吃什么
Hey, where are we going to lunch?
中国菜怎么样
I was thinking Chinese food.
我最爱吃中国菜了
Ohh, I love Chinese!
你怎么知道我爱吃中国菜
How did you know I love Chinese?!
她真可爱  你可以把她塞进口袋里
She is so cute! You could fit her right in your little pocket!
我不知道  我很喜欢她
I don't know. I mean I like her a lot,
她人很好  但是
and she's really nice, but...
但是怎样
But what?
她老爱打我
She keeps punching me.
用她刚才那种可爱的方式吗
In that cute, little, sweet way she just did?
力道比表面上大多了  好吗
Hey, it's a lot harder than it looks! Okay?
她把我打痛了
She-she-she's hurting me.
我知道了  你需要保镖
I know what you need, you need a bodyguard.
罗斯  本幼儿园放学后有事吗
Hey Ross, what is Ben doing after preschool?
别这样  乔伊有烦恼
Hey listen, come on, Joey is having a problem!
他被个小女孩揍了
A little girl is beating him up.
乔伊  过来
Aww, Joey, come here.  Look
亲爱的  我知道你一定非常难受
honey, I know this must be really, really difficult for you and I--
抱歉  我握痛你了吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Am I hurting you?
我带了乔迁之礼来
I brought you some house warming gifts.
盐  让你的生活永远有味
Yeah. Salt, so your life always has flavor.
面包  让你永不饥饿
Bread, so you never go hungry.
浴室用香薰蜡烛
And a scented candle for the bathroom,
用处你知道的
because well, y'know.
谢谢  谢谢  再次感谢
Thanks. Thanks. And thanks again.
欢迎你搬进来  我是史提夫·沙拉
Welcome to the building. I'm uh, Steve Sarah;
楼管会主席
I'm president of the tenants committee.
你好  我是罗斯·盖勒  这是我朋友菲比
Oh hi! Ross Geller. And this is my friend Phoebe.
菲比你好
Oh hi Phoebe.
主席先生
Mr. President.
我来跟你谈霍华德的事
I came to talk to you about Howard.
霍华德
Howard?
他是这里的杂工
Yeah, he's the handy man.
下星期退休
He's gonna be retiring next week
这里的住户决定每人交一百元
and everyone who lives here is kicking in a 100 bucks
感谢他多年来的辛劳
as a thank you for all the hard work type of thing.
真有人情味
Oh that's nice.
是啊  所以你想开支票还是...
Yeah. So, do you want to give a check? Or...
你不必现在给我
Oh look, you don't have to give it too me right now!
你可以从我家门缝塞进去
You can slip it under my door.
不是那样的  我才刚搬来
No-no, it's not that, it's just... I-I just moved in.
他在这里工作了二十五年了
Well, the guy's worked here for 25 years.
但我才搬进来二十五分钟
Yes, but I've lived here for 25 minutes.
好的  我懂了
Oh, okay, I get it.
等等  听我说
No wait, look. Look!
我很抱歉  但我甚至没见过霍华德
I'm sorry, it's just I've never even met Howard.
我不认识霍华德
I-I mean I don't know Howard.
霍华德是这里的杂务工人
Howard's the handy man!
但对我来说他只是个人
Yes but to me he's just, man.
好  随便
Okay, fine, whatever.
欢迎你搬进来
Welcome to the building.
真是有够扯的
Ugh, can you believe that guy!
是啊  我很喜欢他的眼镜
Yeah. I really like his glasses.
史提夫主席逢人就说我吝啬
...so then President Steve told everyone that I was a cheapskate,
现在整栋楼的人都讨厌我
and now the whole building hates me!
有小孩朝我的膝盖吐口水
A little kid spit on my knee!
你猜怎样  我要办一场派对
Y'know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna throw a party.
邀请整栋楼的人
That's right. For everyone in the building,
我要请他们坐下  告诉他们
and I'm gonna sit them all down and explain to them,
我不是坏人  我不是吝啬鬼
I am not a bad guy. I am not a cheap guy!
我只是个坚持理念的人
I'm just a guy who-who stands up for what he believes in.
有原则的人
A man with principles.
听起来真好玩
Sounds like a fun party.
罗斯  如果你希望邻居们喜欢你
Look, Ross, if you want your neighbors to like you,
为什么不付钱算了
why don't you just pay the hundred bucks?
办一场派对可不止一百块
The party's gonna cost you way more than that.
那不重要
It doesn't matter!
这是原则问题  重点是我的原则
It's my principles! We're talking about my principles!
好吧  我以为重点是讨邻居喜欢
Okay, I thought it was about your neighbors liking you.
等他们参加过我的派对就会喜欢我了
Oh, they'll like me. Once they come to my awesome par-tay!
我得走了  我要去买姓名贴
Okay, I gotta run. I gotta go get some nametags.
那个疯狂的派对动物会是你的大舅子
And that crazy party animal will be your brother-in-law.
真幽默  但别对着莫妮卡讲
Very, very funny, but don't say things like that in front of Monica.
别让她有那些念头
I don't want you putting any ideas in her head.
钱德勒  你应该知道她可能本来
Umm, Chandler, you do realize that those ideas
就有那种念头了
are probably already in Monica's head.
为什么
Wh-wh-why?!
因为她爱你  你也爱她
Well, because she loves you and because you love her.
那又怎样呢
Yeah, so, what's that supposed to mean?!
钱德勒  别怕
Hey, Chandler, don't freak out!
我只是在讲你知道的事
I'm telling you something you already know!
她跟理查德分手
Come on, she broke up with Richard
就是因为他不要孩子
because he didn't want to have babies.
她是个女人  快三十岁了
And she's a woman, and she's almost 30,
而且她是莫妮卡
and y'know it's Monica.
我不是那样看的
I don't see it that way. Okay?
我看到两个莫妮卡  朋友的莫妮卡
Because, I see two Monicas, the one that was my friend,
住在对面  想生一大堆小孩
who lived across the hall, and wanted to have a lot of babies
另一个新的莫妮卡  刚跟我交住
and then the new Monica, who I just started to date.
谁晓得她想要什么
Now, who's to say what she wants?!
我没错  我没错  我说得没错吧
I'm right. I'm right. Am I right?
你没错  你当然没错
No, you're right, you are absolutely right.
这让情况完全不同了
I mean that makes, that makes everything different.
一点也没有不同  对吧
It's not different at all, is it?
除非"不同"等于"一样"
Not unless different means the same.
你跟那个服务生好逗哦  你真是个疯子
You were so funny with that waiter! You're such a nut!
扮吸血鬼本来就好笑
Y'know, breadstick fangs are always funny.
是你让它变好笑的  是你好笑
No, you make them funny. You're the funny one!
凯蒂  我们得沟通一下
Uhh, look Katie, uh listen, we-we need to talk. Okay?
我喜欢你  我真的很喜欢你
Umm, look I like you. I-I really do, I like you a lot. Okay?
但有时  你这样开玩笑似的打我
But sometimes when you, when you playfully punch me like that
我感觉就像被一支很小
it-it feels like someone's hitting me with a very tiny
但很结实的球棒打到
but very real bat.
我哪能把你打痛
Aww, like I could hurt you.
你在取笑我的身材吗
Are you making fun of my size?
不要取笑我的身材
Don't make fun of me because of my size!
这种感觉真好
Isn't this great?
真想永远这样
Couldn't you just stay like this forever?
钱德勒  你想不想永远这样
Chandler! Couldn't you just stay here forever?
这样  那样  哪样都可以
Yeah, here, somewhere else, y'know where-where ever.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我很好  很随性
Yeah, I'm cool. Casual.
你在干什么
What-what are you doing?
只是随便混混  开心下
I'm just hanging out. Y'know, having fun.
跟我随性交住的你在一起
Y'know with the girl that I'm seeing casually.
我就知道  我就知道你会这样
Man, I knew it! I knew you were going to do this!!
怎样
What?!
大家一拿结婚什么的开玩笑
Get all freaked out because everybody was talking
你就会被吓坏
and just joking around about marriage and stuff.
你的确想要那些事  对吗
Well, you do want all that stuff, right?
你知道我想要什么
Oh and you know what I want!
没错  你想要小孩  你有孩子狂爱症
Yes! You want babies! You have baby fever!
我才没有孩子狂爱症
I do not have baby fever!
拜托  你超迷恋小孩和婚姻
Oh please, you are obsessed with babies and-and marriage
和一切跟小孩和婚姻有关的事
and everything that's related to babies and-and marriage!
我有个好提议
I've got an good idea,
把这个高压锅的炉火关掉吧
why don't we turn down the heat on this pressure cooker?!
你疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
钱德勒  这不是我的问题
Chandler, this isn't about me! This is about you
是你不敢做出承诺
and all your weird relationship commitment crap!
少来  我了解你
Nah-uh! I know you! Okay?
我知道你脑袋里在想什么
I know the thoughts that you have in the head--in your head!
你并非什么都知道
You don't know everything.
你知道我今晚要陪的人不是你  而是瑞秋吗
Did you know that I'm going out with Rachel tonight instead of you?
你知道这里唯一的小孩是你吗
And did you know that the only baby around here is you?!
你知道我现在连看都不想看你吗
And did you know that I can't even look at you right now?!
那我倒是不知道
Well, I did not know that.
不会有事吧  她不会离开我吧
It's gonna be okay, right? I mean she's not gonna leave me?
这是可以解决的
This is, this is fixable.
当然  肯定了
Oh yeah, yeah, sure. Absolutely.
我可以解决
By me?
不可能
Oh, no! No-no.
除非你有大动作
Well, unless you make some kind of big gesture.
要非常大
Yeah, big!
女主角来了
Uh-oh, shht! The Misses.
甘瑟  我要一杯咖啡  外带
Gunther, can I get a coffee  to go?
莫妮卡
Monica.
我还是不想跟你说话
I'm still not done not wanting to talk to you.
告诉我怎样弥补
Just tell me what I need to do to make things right.
什么
What?!
我们一直这样  我做错事
Well, that's what we do. Y'know, I-I mess up
你教我怎么补救  我补救完
and then you tell me how to fix it and then I do
你又觉得我很可爱
and then y'know you think I'm all cute again.
我不想再当你的爱情指导了
Really? I'm really tired of being your relationship tutor.
这次你得自己想  好吗
You're gonna have to figure this one for yourself. All right?
如果你害怕真正的恋爱
Y'know what? If you're too afraid to be in a real relationship,
那就别谈
then don't be in one.
霍华德  霍华德...
Howard! Howard! Howard!...
-菲比  -罗斯
- Phoebe. - Ross.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我以为这是你的派对
Oh, I thought this was your party
结果是替霍华德办的派对
and it turns out it's a party for Howard.
他真是个老可爱
He's just the sweetest little man!
-菲比再见  谢谢你出钱  -不客气
-See ya Phoebe! Oh and hey, thanks for chipping in! - Sure.
你出了钱
You chipped in?!
对  一百块
Yeah, uh-huh, a 100 dollars.
菲比  你居然给他们钱
Phoebe! I can't believe you gave them money!
你不是也同意  他们要我出钱
I thought you agreed it was totally unreasonable
很不合理吗
that they asked me for that money!
对  但他们没要我出
Yeah, but they didn't ask me!
我只是个外来的大方的陌生人
Y'know? This way I'm just y'know, the exotic, generous stranger.
最好玩了
That's always fun to be.
但你这样显得我更差劲
Yeah, but you're making me look bad!
谁说的  我是在帮你加分
No I'm not. No! If anything I'm making you look better!
他们会看见你在跟我说话  我可是大红人
They'll see you talking to me and that's--I'm a hit!
菲比
Oh hey, Pheebs!
罗斯
Oh hey, Ross.
我在想  你们或许可以交换住处
Umm, see, I was thinking maybe you two could switch apartments
菲比跟我们比较合得来
because Phoebe's more our kind of people.
你考虑一下
Something to think about.
是我不好
Yeah, okay, my bad.
哇  你看起来好壮
Wow! You look, you look...big.
谢谢  最近我有健身
Thanks! I've been working out.
看得出来我穿了六件毛衣吗
Hey listen, is it obvious that I'm wearing six sweaters?
看得出来  但看不出来为什么
Uhhh, yeah. But it's not obvious why.
我要跟凯蒂分手
Well look, I'm breaking up with Katie
所以得多加几层防护
so I had to put on some extra padding.
她平常高兴就会打我
Y'know? I mean, if she hits me when she's happy,
现在我要收回乔伊之爱
can you imagine how hard she's gonna hit me
她岂不是打得更用力吗
when I tell her I'm taking away the Joey love?
好可爱的外套
Hey! Hey, cute jacket!
谢谢  你真好
Oh, thanks! That's so sweet!
是乔伊要你叫痛的吗
Oh, ow! Did Joey tell you to say that?
你们真是够了
You guys, are too much!
你知道吗  凯蒂  说真的
Y'know what Katie? I gotta tell ya
我觉得你才够了
I-I-I-I think you are the one who is too much.
乔伊的朋友真棒
Ohh, Joey has the nicest friends!
女朋友更棒
Ohh, and the nicest girlfriend!
你真好
You're so sweet!
你才好
Ohh, you're so sweet!
乔伊  她踢我
Joey, she just kicked me.
你不替我出头吗
Well? Aren't you gonna do something?
你最好替我出头
You'd better do something,
否则我现在就走人
or I'm gonna walk out that door right now!
你快行动啊
Well? Are you gonna?
算了
Nah.
菲比
Phoebe.
菲比  菲比
Phoebe, Phoebe.
这真是人间地狱  我要走了
Look, this is a disaster! Can't I please just go?
不行  我正在帮你说好话
No! No! I'm talking you up to people.
再等一下下
Just give it a little time, all right?
放轻松  吃点东西  好吗
Relax, get something to eat! Okay?
你跟他们说了我什么
So uh, what did you tell them about me?
我说了你和艾蜜莉的事
Oh, I was telling them about you and Emily.
好争取同情心
Y'know, try to get some sympathy.
但讲一讲你成了坏人
But somehow you came off as the bad guy.
什么
What?!
我想我说的方式不对
Yeah, I think I told it wrong.
我们应该先聊聊
Y'know, we should talk about that
我不太知道前因后果
because I don't totally understand what happened there.
这个蛋糕真好吃
Ohh, this cake is really good!
看吧  情况已经在好转了
Oh, okay, see? Things are looking up already!
天哪  有人切了霍华德的蛋糕
Oh my God! Someone cut Howard's cake!
谁会做这种低级的事
Who would do a think like that?
3-B房
3-B!
你白吃白喝  扫了大家的兴
Okay, you got your free food! You ruined everyone's fun!
是不是该回家了
Don't you think it's time you went home?!
快走
Yeah, leave!
滚回3-B去  3-B
Go back to 3-B, 3-B!
大家冷静一下  冷静下
All right, everyone calm down! Everyone calm down!
我有话要说
I have something that I would like to say!
这里有谁喜欢罗斯
Who here likes Ross?
你们当然不喜欢他
Of course you don't like him!
他不交钱
He-he didn't give you any money,
我问有谁喜欢他  他自己举手
he raised his own hand when I asked, "Who hear likes Ross,"
他还贴两个姓名牌
and he's wearing two nametags!
老实说  刚开始认识罗斯时
I-I'll be honest with you guys, when I first met Ross
我一点也不喜欢他
I didn't like him at all!
但后来了解他后
But then once I got to know him
我就发现他很好
I saw that he's really sweet
很关心人  很大方
and caring and very generous.
请不要在还不了解他时
I mean, all I'm saying is don't judge Ross
就断定他的人品
before you get to know him all right?
我现在很喜欢你们
I mean, I like all you guys now,
但是刚见面时  寇特
but when I first meet you y'know Kurt
我觉得你是讨厌的酒鬼
I thought, y'know abrasive drunk,
萝拉  笨得令人傻眼
umm Lola, mind numbingly stupid!
还有你们  拜金女配老牛吃嫩草的变态
And okay, you guys Gold-digger, cradle robbing perv!
你们懂我的意思了吧
So, I think you all know what I mean.
我没想到他们会冲咱们扔东西
Obviously I didn't think they were gonna start throwing things.
我只是想我一直羞辱他们
I just thought if I kept insulting everyone,
你就会跳出来帮他们
you would jump in and defend everyone
那就可以变成英雄啦
and then you could look like the hero.
哇  是啊  太深奥了我不明白
Oh wow, yeah! See, I did not get that.
莫妮卡呢  她在哪里  我有话跟她说
Where's Monica?! Where is she? I need to talk to her!
我有急事  她在吗
It's urgent! Is she here?
我就是莫妮卡
I'm Monica.
我有急事要跟你说
I need to talk to you, it's urgent!
我想了很多我们的事
Okay, I've been doing a lot of thinking about us,
想了你和我的事
y'know a lot of uhh, us thinking.
我猜只有一个办法
And uh, well I guess there's only one-one way to do this.
你要干什么
Wait what-wh-wh-what are you doing?!
莫妮卡
Monica...
拜托不要
No-no, don't-don't-don't do it!
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
什么馊主意
What a bad idea!
我不敢看
Ohhhh, I cannot look at it!
钱德勒  你为什么要这样
Chandler, why are you doing this?
我不知道  但我知道我不怕做这个
I don't know. But I know I'm not afraid to do this.
钱德勒
Chandler.
因为我很抱歉吗
I'm doing this because I'm sorry?
你真的觉得
Do you umm, you really think
结婚的最好理由是因为你很抱歉吗
the best reason to get married is because you're sorry?
不  最好的理由是奉子成婚
No, the best reason to get married is pregnancy.
"抱歉"大约排第四
Sorry is pretty much fourth y'know,
排在"准备好了"和"真的想结婚"后面
behind being ready and actually wanting to get married.
你愿意做我的妻子吗
Will you be my wife?
钱德勒  你先静下来想想
Chandler, umm, I want you to take just a minute
这件事有多荒谬
and I want you to think about how ridiculous this sounds.
我的确有点希望他们都不在
Yeah, I'm kinda wishing everyone wasn't here right now.
亲爱的  这些事都不是我扯出来的
Honey! Do you know that none of that stuff came from me?!
我从来没说现在就想结婚生子
I mean I never said I wanted to have babies and get married right now!
但我真的很乱
Yeah I know, but I was really confused
后来又跟他们谈过
and then I talked to these guys.
离婚两次的人和乔伊
Who? Two divorces and Joey?!
她说得对
She's right y'know.
但这种奚落算什么
Yeah, but still, cheap shot!
你知道吗  我不是要你
Y'know what? Y'know when I said that I want you to
自己想该怎么做吗
deal with this relationship stuff all on your own?
你还做不到这一点
Well, you're not ready for that.
我也这么认为
I didn't think I was!
天哪  要是我答应了呢
Oh my God, what would have done if I said yes?
那我会很开心
Well I would've been happy
能跟心爱的女人
because I would've be able to spend the rest of my life
共度下半生
with the woman that I love.
或者你会在那扇门上看到我的人形窟窿
Or, you would've seen a Chandler shaped hole in that door.
罗斯  请把刀子给我
Hey Ross, will you pass me that knife?
我才不要
No, I will not!
你不必这么凶吧
Oh, it's okay. You don't have to be so mean about it.
你说得对  对不起  嫁给我好吗
You're right, I'm sorry. Will you marry me?
我正想向你求婚
Aw, and I was gonna ask you to marry me
因为我上星期忘了跟你打招呼了
because I forgot to say hello to you last week.
菲比  我想那种情况应该
Oh no wait Pheebs, I think for something like that
只需要同居
you just ask them to move in with you.
但我也不确定  你说呢钱德勒
But I'm not sure, Chandler?
好了  我还要被笑多久
Okay, how long is this going to go on.
那得看你做的事
Well I think the length of teasing is
有多荒唐  所以  会很久
directly related to how insane you were so, a long time.
真好玩  瑞秋
This is fun. Hey Rach,
记得"我们分手了"那件事吗
remember that whole "We were on a break thing?"
我很抱歉  嫁给我好吗
Well, I'm sorry, will you marry me?
不好笑
That's not funny.